Register of the Frederick L. Anderson papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- U.S. Strategic Air Forces in Europe, Headquarters File, 1943-1945
  - Report of the Commanding General to the Joint Chiefs of Staff, European Section, 1945
    - October 15 (Box-folder 84: 7-8)
    - October 25 (Box-folder 84: 9)
  - Report of Investigation of Tactical Bombing, 1944 July 25 (Box-folder 84: 10)
  - Requirements for air bases and privileges for U.S. Air Forces in Europe during the occupation period, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 85: 1)
  - Results of operations, 1944
    - March (Box-folder 85: 2)
    - April (Box-folder 85: 3-4)
    - May (Box-folder 85: 5)
    - June (Box-folder 86: 1-2)
    - July (Box-folder 86: 3)
  - Royal Air Force, No. 54 Base, report on liaison with U.S.A.A.F., 1944 March-June (Box-folder 86: 4)
  - Staff Reference Manual (Box-folder 86: 5-6)
  - Staff study on proposed transfer of Fifteenth Air Force units to U.K. or the continent, 1945 January (Box-folder 86: 7)
  - Standard Operating Procedure, Eastern Command, undated (Box-folder 86: 8)
  - Statistical control, 1944 (Box-folder 86: 9)
  - Strategic Intelligence Branch, Evaluation of Military Effects of R.A.F. Bombing of Germany, 1943 (Box-folder 87: 1)
  - Summary of Combat Crews, 1944 (Box-folder 87: 2)
  - "Talisman" Plan, 1944 August (Box-folder 87: 3)
  - U.S. Army Air Forces in Europe, 1944 (Box-folder 87: 4)
  - U.S.S.T.A.F. History, 1945 May-June (Box-folder 87: 5)
- Subject File, 1917-1947
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, studies, clippings, printed matter, and other materials, arranged alphabetically.
  - AAF Scientific Advisory Group, 1946 May
    - Explosives and Terminal Ballistics (Box-folder 88: 1)
    - Guidance and Homing of Missiles and Pilotless Aircraft (Box-folder 88: 2)
  - Air Corps, Army, Justifications of Estimates, Fiscal Year 1947 (Box-folder 88: 3-4)
  - Air Corps Replacement Center (Aircrew), program of instruction, course for Aircraft Observer Candidates (Striking Force), 1941 August (Box-folder 88: 5)
  - Air Corps technical schools, physics test (Box-folder 88: 6)
  - Air Member for Personnel Department (Box-folder 88: 7)
  - Air operations
    - General, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 88: 8)
    - In support of Ground forces in North-West Africa, 1943 March-April (Box-folder 88: 9)
  - Air power articles, 1917-1943 (Box-folder 88: 10-11)
  - Air protection, relief, maintenance, and evacuation of prisoners of war, 1944 December (Box-folder 89: 1)
  - Air Route Guide - Alaska (including British Columbia and Yukon Territory), 1942 March 15 (Box-folder 89: 2-3)
  - Air surrender documents, 1945 (Box-folder 89: 4)
  - "The Air War - People and References to Consult With Regard to Different Phases,", 1945 (Box-folder 89: 5)
  - Aircraft status reports, 1942 (Box-folder 89: 6)
  - Alaska Inspection, 1942 (Box-folder 89: 7)
  - American-British strategy, 1942 November (Box-folder 89: 8)
  - Andrews, Frank M. (Box-folder 89: 9)
  - "Aphrodite" Project, 1944 July-December (Box-folder 89: 10)
  - Army Air Forces
    - Aircraft deliveries and production, 1942 (Box-folder 89: 11)
    - Expansion schedule for 1943 (Box-folder 89: 12)
    - Link trainers, 1942 (Box-folder 89: 13)
    - Office of Commanding General, Air Operations Briefs, Volume 7, 1945 May 21 (Box-folder 89: 14)
    - Ordnance equipment, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 90: 1)
    - Organizational charts, 1942 (Box-folder 90: 2)
    - Personnel, Officers, 1942
      - General (Box-folder 90: 3)
      - Recommendations for promotions (Box-folder 90: 4)
    - "Radar and Communications,", 1946 May (Box-folder 90: 5)
    - Schedules for aircraft and crews, 1942 (Box-folder 90: 6)
  - Arnold, Henry H., statement at press conference, 1943 October 18 (Box-folder 90: 7)
  - Arpaia, Michael (Box-folder 90: 8)
  - Attacks against submarine manufacturing and operating installations, 1945 (Box-folder 90: 9)
  - Automatic flight control equipment, bomb sights training, 1941 February (Box-folder 90: 10)
  - Baldwin, Richard H. (Box-folder 90: 11)
  - Baum, Jack L. (Box-folder 90: 12)
  - Berliner, Henry (Box-folder 90: 13)
  - Bessell Board Report, 1946 January (Box-folder 90: 14)
  - Biennial Report of the Chief of Staff of the United States Army, to the Secretary of War, July 1, 1941 to June 30, 1943 (Box-folder 90: 15)
  - Bombardier and combat crew training, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 90: 16)
  - Bombardier training programs in the United States, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 90: 17)
  - Bombardiers, 1942 (Box-folder 90: 18)
  - Bombardment crews, 1942 (Box-folder 90: 19)
  - Bombardment Groups, inspections, 1942 (Box-folder 90: 20)
  - Bombardment Tactical Committee, 1942 (Box-folder 90: 21)
  - Bomber offensive against Germany, undated (Box-folder 91: 1)
  - Bombing ability of the German Air Force, 1942 January (Box-folder 91: 2)
  - Bombing Accuracy Board, 1941
    - General (Box-folder 91: 3)
    - Report, January 2 (Box-folder 91: 4)
  - Bombing Board report on trip to England, 1941 December 17 (Box-folder 91: 5)
  - Bombing in Europe by U.S. Air Forces, 1940s (Box-folder 91: 6)
  - Bombs and fuses (Box-folder 91: 7)
  - Booth, David F. (Box-folder 91: 8)
  - British bombing equipment and tactics, 1940s (Box-folder 91: 9)
  - British Royal Air Force (R.A.F.), 1941 (Box-folder 91: 10)
  - Brockway, Mortimer (Box-folder 91: 11)
  - "Buzzing the Golden Windows - The City Between Bridges (Venice of the North) - Being the Social Itinerary of a Flight to the Isles of Song,", 1945 (Box-folder 91: 12)
  - Cable Traffic - Traffic Air Force Organization, 1944 August (Box-folder 91: 13)
  - Carpet bombing, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 91: 14)
  - Columbia University, Applied Mathematics Group, "Ricochet Off Water: A Memorandum Submitted to the National Defense Research Committee,", 1944 May (Box-folder 91: 15)
  - Combined bomber offensive, 1945 January (Box-folder 91: 16)
  - Combined bomber offensive from the United Kingdom, 1944 December (Box-folder 91: 17)
  - Combined Strategic Targets Committee, Working Committee, Bulletin No. 1945-19, 1945 June 21 (Box-folder 91: 18)
  - Command materials, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 91: 19)
  - Command of the U.S. Army Air Forces Operating Against Germany, 1944 June (Box-folder 91: 20)
  - Commendations, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 91: 21)
  - Control of strategic bomber forces in Europe following the establishment of Allied Forces on the continent, 1944 September (Box-folder 91: 22)
  - Cooper, Robert E. (Box-folder 91: 23)
  - Creighton, Neal (Box-folder 91: 24)
  - Crimea Conference report, White House, 1945 February 12 (Box-folder 91: 25)
  - "The Development of Tactical Bombardment Formations: Report of the Army Air Forces Board,", 1943 July 15 (Box-folder 91: 26)
  - D/F bearing converter, Serial No. 151 (Box-folder 92: 1)
  - Drift meter ground speed computer (Box-folder 92: 2)
  - "Eclipse" Memorandum No. 18, War Criminals and Security Suspects, 1945 January (Box-folder 92: 3)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., Remarks on Demobilization, 1946 January 15 (Box-folder 92: 4)
  - Estimated U.S. Navy carrier bomb tonnages on Japanese homeland for 1945 (Box-folder 92: 5)
  - Estimation of Force Required to Neutralize Axis Targets, 1943 March (Box-folder 92: 6-7)
  - Fahey, James C., The Ships and Aircraft of the United States Fleet, 1942 (Box-folder 92: 8)
  - Falk, Lawrence L. (Box-folder 92: 9)
  - First United States Army, Report of Operations, 1943 October 20 - 1944 August 1
    - Book I (Box-folder 92: 10)
    - Annex No. 2 (Box-folder 92: 11)
    - Annex No. 2 (Box-folder 93: 1)
    - Annex Nos. 12-14 (Box-folder 93: 2)
    - Annex Nos. 15-20 (Box-folder 93: 3)
  - Flight manuals, models B-25C and B-25D bombardment airplanes (Box-folder 93: 4)
  - "Flyaways,", 1942 March-April (Box-folder 93: 5)
  - Foote, Edward P. (Box-folder 93: 6)
  - General supplies and relationship of depot supply to organization, undated (Box-folder 93: 7)
  - General Wedemeyer's idea, undated (Box-folder 93: 8)
  - German Air Force (Box-folder 93: 9)
  - German aircraft industry, 1945 (Box-folder 93: 10)
  - German bombing of British Isles, 1941 October (Box-folder 93: 11)
  - German jet aircraft (Box-folder 93: 12)
  - German strategy and capacity to resist, 1945 January (Box-folder 93: 13)
  - Handbook for Bombardiers, 1941 March 31 (Box-folder 93: 14)
  - Helicopters (Box-folder 93: 15)
  - Honors and ceremonies (Box-folder 93: 16)
  - Hopper, Bruce, "Sweden: A Case Study in Small State Neutrality,", 1945 January (Box-folder 94: 1)
  - Index to files (Box-folder 94: 2)
  - Instruction programs for aerial bombardiers and pilots, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 94: 3)
  - Investigation of the "heavy" crossbow installations in Northern France - Report by the Sanders Mission to the chairman of the Crossbow Committee, 1945 February 21 (Box-folder 94: 4)
  - Itineraries, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 94: 5)
  - Kirk, Charles G. (Box-folder 94: 6)
  - Kirkendall, Mr. (Box-folder 94: 7)
  - Lowry Field, Denver, Colorado
    - 1940 (Box-folder 94: 8)
    - 1941 (Box-folder 94: 9)
  - Manby R.A.F. Station (Box-folder 94: 10)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, radio equipment studies, 1942 (Box-folder 94: 11-12)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, radio equipment studies, 1942 (Box-folder 95: 1)
  - Maximum effort against Japan and Japanese shipping, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 95: 2)
  - Maxson, Herburt (Box-folder 95: 3)
  - Meeting of Chief of the Air Staff, Army Air Forces, and Theater Air Commanders, 1945 January 11 (Box-folder 95: 4)
  - Meetings, 1944 December 23 (Box-folder 95: 5)
  - Memoranda for Director of Bombardment, 1943 January-February (Box-folder 95: 6)
  - Meyers, Joseph F. (Box-folder 95: 7)
  - Military insurance, estates and wills, 1941 July (Box-folder 95: 8)
  - Minikus, Fred (Box-folder 95: 9)
  - Monetary receipts
    - 1943-1944 (Box-folder 95: 10)
    - 1944-1945 (Box-folder 95: 11)
  - Morgan, H. W. (Box-folder 95: 12)
  - Ninth Air Force in the European Theater of Operations, 1946 March (Box-folder 95: 13)
  - Operation "Agonaut,", 1945 (Box-folder 95: 14)
  - Operation "Clarion,", 1944-1945 (Box-folder 96: 1)
  - Operation "Thunderclap,", 1944 August-October (Box-folder 96: 2)
  - Operations north of the Ruhr, 1945 March (Box-folder 96: 3)
  - O.S.S. London, R & A Branch, War Diary - "Economic Outpost With Economic Warfare Division," Vol. 5, 1945 April (Box-folder 96: 4)
  - Papers to be taken by General Anderson to Yalta (Box-folder 96: 5)
  - Personnel, records of individuals, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 96: 6)
  - Pilotless aircraft and rockets, 1944 July-November (Box-folder 96: 7)
  - Pilots Handbook of Flight Operating Instructions for Models B-24C, B-24D, B-24E, 1942 September 15 (Box-folder 96: 8)
  - Pilots Information File (flying safety manual), 1943 (Box-folder 96: 9)
  - Plan for the use of strategic air forces - Mid-March until V-Day, 1945 (Box-folder 97: 1)
  - Planned utilization of heavy bombers delivered and available to AAF, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 97: 2)
  - Precision Bombing Practice, technical manual, 1942 May 28 (Box-folder 97: 3)
  - Proposed Air Policy of the United States - Civil and Military, 1944 December 22 (Box-folder 97: 4)
  - Proposed International Air Policy of the United States and a Discussion of Necessary Compromises, 1945 January (Box-folder 97: 5)
  - Radar Planning Device Conavaer No. 30-160R-28 (Box-folder 97: 6)
  - Radius of action computer (Box-folder 97: 7)
  - Receipts for documents, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 97: 8)
  - Redeployment
    - General, 1944 (Box-folder 97: 9-10)
    - Redeployment Forecast - Atlantic Section, 1945 February 20 (Box-folder 97: 11)
    - Requirements of flight echelons from European Theater of Operations over air transport command routes, 1945 January (Box-folder 97: 12)
    - Schedule of Army Air Force Units in European Theater of Operations, U.S. Strategic Air Forces in Europe Planning Directives, 1945 March 15 (Box-folder 97: 13)
      - No. 1, 1945 January (Box-folder 97: 14)
      - No. 3, 1945 March (Box-folder 97: 15)
  - Report of air attacks on targets in Dresden, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 97: 16)
  - Report of the Assistant Chief of Air Staff, Personnel, to the Commanding General, Army Air Forces, May 1, 1945 - June 30, 1946 (Box-folder 98: 1)
  - Report of the Commanding General of the Army Air Forces to the Secretary of War, 1944 January (Box-folder 98: 2)
  - Reports of status of aircraft, 1942
    - July 31 - August 2 (Box-folder 98: 3)
    - August 30 - September 1 (Box-folder 98: 4)
    - September 1-2 (Box-folder 98: 5)
    - September 14-16 (Box-folder 98: 6)
  - Review of Operations of the Working Committee (Communications) Combined Strategic Targets Committee, 1944 October - 1945 May (Box-folder 98: 7)
  - Root, Ned (Box-folder 98: 8)
  - Royal Air Force Bombing Analysis Unit, Survey of Bomb Damage to Coastal Batteries Between Le Havre and Abbeville, 1945 April (Box-folder 98: 9)
  - Seventh Bombardment Group, Air Corps, Hamilton Field, CA
    - Coastal Frontier Defensive Exercise, No. 2, 1936 (Box-folder 99: 1-2)
    - Coordinated Defensive Fires, 1940 April (Box-folder 99: 3)
    - Memoranda and orders
      - 1935-36 (Box-folder 99: 4)
      - 1936 (Box-folder 99: 5)
      - 1937
        - January-July (Box-folder 99: 6)
        - August (Box-folder 99: 7)
        - September (Box-folder 99: 8)
      - 1938 (Box-folder 99: 9)
    - Plan for Defense Against Chemical Attack, 1938 (Box-folder 100: 1)
    - Report of GHQ Air Force Exercises, 1937 May (Box-folder 100: 2)
    - Tactical Doctrine, 1941 (Box-folder 100: 3)
  - Seventieth Group Program, 1945 (Box-folder 100: 4)
  - Sicily, requirement for offensive operations against, undated (Box-folder 100: 5)
  - Smith, Milton J. (Box-folder 100: 6)
  - Social affairs, 1943 (Box-folder 100: 7-9)
  - Sorensen, Edgar P., "The Application of Air Power,", 1943 June 16 (Box-folder 100: 10)
  - Spaatz, Carl, 1945 (Box-folder 100: 11)
  - Special War Department Monthly Reports on Airplanes, 1942
    - April (Box-folder 100: 12)
    - April (Box 101: 1)
    - May (Box-folder 101: 2-3)
  - Spruance, Admiral, talk to National War College, 1947 January 8 (Box-folder 101: 4)
  - Standard Operating Procedure, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 101: 5)
  - Supreme Headquarters, Allied Expeditionary Force, Handbook Governing Policy and Procedure for the Military Occupation of Germany, 1944 December (Box-folder 101: 6)
  - Swedish operations, 1945 April (Box-folder 101: 7)
  - Tactical Program, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 101: 8)
  - Target inspection tour in Germany, 1945 April 17-22 (Box-folder 101: 9)
  - Third Bombardment Group (Light), Headquarters (Box-folder 101: 10)
  - Thirty-Ninth Bombardment Group, Headquarters
    - General (Box-folder 101: 11)
    - Training program, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 101: 12)
  - Timed turn indicator (Box-folder 101: 13)
  - Tomlinson, Frederick, "Strategic Bombing May Be the Only Way to Shorten War,", 1945 January (Box-folder 101: 14)
  - Training Board Reports, 1941 (Box-folder 102: 1-2)
  - Twelfth Air Force, proposed movement of, 1945 January (Box-folder 102: 3)
  - Unification of the armed forces (equal status of the Army, Navy, and Air Force), 1946-1947 (Box-folder 102: 4-7)
  - Unification of the armed forces (equal status of the Army, Navy, and Air Force), 1946-1947 (Box-folder 103: 1)
  - U.S. Air Forces, United Kingdom, Intelligence Summary for the Week Ending December 5, 1943 (Box-folder 103: 2)
  - U.S. Army Air Forces
    - Air Transport Command, Plans and Policies Relating to ATC Routes and Services in the European Theater, 1945 January 1 (Box-folder 103: 3)
    - Office of Statistical Control, Analysis of Alternative Vehicles in a Stratetic Air Campaign, 1946 June 6 (Box-folder 103: 4)
    - Organization and command, 1944 August-September (Box-folder 103: 5)
  - U.S. Army
    - European Theater of Operations, Headquarters, Theater Directives, 1944 April (Box-folder 103: 6)
    - First Army, Report of Operations, 1944 August 1 - 1945 February 22 (Box-folder 103: 7-8)
  - U.S. post-war military and civil air policies in Europe, 1945 January (Box-folder 103: 9)
  - U.S.-Soviet relations, report of the Quantico Vulnerabilities Panel, 1955 June (Box-folder 119: 1-2)
  - U.S. Strategic Air Forces in the European-Mediterranean Area, meetings, 1943 November-December (Box-folder 104: 1)
  - "United States to Great Britain," U.S. Army Air Forces air route manual, 1942 July 29 (Box-folder 104: 2)
  - War Department
    - Adjutant General's Office, Officers of the Army in or Near the District of Columbia, 1941 April (Box-folder 104: 3)
    - Edited Minutes of War Department Conference of Industry, Labor and Newspaper Leaders, Washington, D.C., 1943
      - September 27-28 (Box-folder 104: 4)
      - October 28-29 (Box-folder 104: 5)
  - Weekly summary of flying time for tactical units, 1942 October - 1943 March 19 (Box-folder 104: 6)
  - "Wide Wing - A History," dedicated to the Memory of Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1945 (Box-folder 104: 7)
  - Williamson, C. G., "Separation and Efficiency,", 1943 August 3 (Box-folder 104: 8)
  - Williamson, Colonel, correspondence and papers, 1944 July (Box-folder 104: 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 104: 10)
- Oversize File, 1942-1944
  Volumes containing aerial photographs, graphs, diagrams, and explanatory text relating to bombing operations of the U.S. Army Air Forces.
  - Eighth Air Force
    - Semi-Monthly Report of Operations, 1943 December 1-15 (Box 105)
    - Strategic and Tactical Operations, aerial photographs, 1943-1944
    - Tactical Development, 1942 August - 1945 May
  - Air Corps Tactical School, Maxwell Field, Alabama, bombardment aviation exercises, 1937-1938 (Box 106)
  - Forty-fourth Bomb Group insignia
  - "The Role of H2X on D-Day," by F. L. Anderson, undated (Box 107)
  - U.S. War Department. Army Air Forces
    - Bi-Weekly Station Housing Reports for the Army Air Forces Within the Continental U.S.
      - 1942 October-December
      - 1943 March-April
    - Tactical Planning - Characteristics and Performance Chart, 1943 December 31
  - U.S. Strategic Air Forces in Europe. Headquarters (Box 108)
    - "Attacks on Axis Oil," aerial photographs, 1944 May 1 - June 30
    - Informational volume, undated (Box 109)
    - Operations, aerial photographs, 1944 January-December (Box 110)
    - Target Status Book, aerial photographs, 1943-1944 (Box 111)
    - Targets - Damage Status Book, (aerial photographs), 1942-1944 (Box 112)
- Aerial Photographs, 1943-1945
  Volumes containing aerial photographs depicting bombing operations of the Eighth Air Force and Eighth Bomber Command.
  - Eighth Air Force (On-shelf shelf)
    - Bomb Damage Reports, 1944
    - Bomber missions, 1944
      - May
      - June
      - July
      - September
      - October
      - November
  - Eighth Bomber Command, bomber missions
    - 1943
      - July
      - August
      - September
      - October
      - November
      - December
    - 1944
      - February
      - December
    - 1945
      - January
      - February
- Memorabilia, undated
  - Gas mask (Box 113)
  - Wooden plaques with insignias (Box 114)
  - Uniforms
    - U.S. Air Force flight jacket (leather) (Box 115)
    - U.S. Air Force dress greens (Box 116)
- Photographs, undated
  - 4 photographs of Frederick Anderson, including one with Abraham Chassen (Envelope A)
  - 11 prints of U.S. Air Force officers (Envelope B)
  - 18 prints of individuals and groups of U.S. Air Force personnel (Envelope C)
  - 30 prints of Eighth U.S. Air Force personnel and equipment in Europe, 1943-1945 (Envelope D-E)
    Included are scenes of bombing damage in Germany.
  - 126 prints of Eighth U.S. Air Force personnel and equipment in Europe (Envelope F-O)
    Included are scenes of bombing damage in Germany and France.
  - 11 aerial photos of bomb dropping (Envelope P)
  - 10 aerial photos of bomb damage in Paris, at Renault Works, and Velzen Rail Line in Germany (Envelope Q)
  - 5 prints of damaged U.S. aircraft (Envelope R)
  - 61 prints depicting bomb damage in Germany (Envelope S-X)
  - 9 Aerial photos of bombing attacks on Bad Voslau ME-109 Assembly Plant and Airdrome by 15th U.S. Air Force, 1944 April 23 (Envelope Y)
  - 10 prints of bomb damage to tanks (Envelope ZX)
  - 10 prints of bombs being inspected, loaded into trucks and aircraft and exploding from aerial view (Envelope AA)
  - 6 prints of maps with U.S. Air Force routes over Europe, 1944 (Envelope BB)
  - 61 aerial photos of U.S. Air Force attacks on the German Air Force; heavy industry, and Axis oil installations, 1943-1944 (Album fCC)
  - 14 aerial photos of U.S. Strategic Air Forces in Europe operations, 1944 November (Album fDD)
- Motion Picture Film, undated
  - "Target for Today," U.S. War Department film (black and white)
    - Part 1 (Reel 1)
    - Part 2 (Reel 2)
  - "Victory in the Air," World War II (black and white) (Reel 3)
  - "AAF Special Delivery" (Reel 4)
  - "Bomb Damage," World War II (color), 19 minutes, circa 1942-1945 (Reel 5)
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 75054_f_0001102
    16mm reversal original, silent, edited. Features scenes of bomb damage to a German factory, possibly a ball-bearing factory in Schweinfurt, Germany, a concentration camp, which is most likely the Buchenwald camp near Weimar, Germany, shots of bombers, aerial footage of mountains, land, and sea, and shots of General Henry "Hap" Arnold and General Frederick Anderson.
  - "Operation Titanic," World War II (black and white) (Reel 6)
  - "The Last Bomb," World War II (black and white) (Reel 7)
  - "Thunderbolt," World War II (color), 45 minutes, 1944 (Reel 8)
    Use copy reference number: 75054_f_0001419
    United States War Department film. Depicts the Allied air campaign over Italy.
  - "Target Germany," World War II (black and white) (Reel 9)
  - "The Unknown Battle for General Arnold," World War II (black and white) (Reel 10)
  - Tropical island fishing trip with military personnel present (color) (Reel 11)
  - Home movies depicting golfing games (one black and white and one color) (Reel 12-13)
  - Home movie depicting military personnel (color) (Reel 14)
  - General Anderson giving speech in full military uniform, separate narration included (black and white) (Reel 15)
  - General Anderson giving anti-Soviet speech in civilian clothing (black and white), circa 1950s (Reel 16)
  - U.S. Army Air Forces personnel and planes in action, World War II (black and white) (Reel 17)
  - U.S. Army Air Forces operations in the Pacific, World War II (black and white) (Reel 18)
  - "High Wycombe Staff," World War II (black and white) (Reel 19)
  - "General Anderson and Staff Officers," World War II (color), 18 minutes (Reel 20)
    Use copy reference number: 75054_f_0001420
    Home movie of General Anderson and staff officers World War II. (1) Bury, St. Edmunds; (2) Watermeadows; (3) Marks Hall; (4) visit of King and Queen to Bassingbourne. Unedited, color, silent.
  - Interview with General Anderson after World War II (black and white) (Reel 21)
  - "Secretary Stimson's Tour," World War II (color) (Reel 22)
  - "Elveden Hall, " World War II (black and white), 1943 (Reel 23)
  - "London, Churchill's Daughter" (color), 12 minutes, circa 1942-1945 (Reel 24)
    Use copy reference number: 75054_f_0002067
    16mm reversal original, silent, edited. Features footage of Winston Churchill’s daughter, Mary Churchill Soames, grandson, Winston Spencer-Churchill, and daughter-in-law, Pamela Churchill Harriman, scenes of city streets, buildings, landmarks, and countryside in Great Britain, and scenes of the christening of the B-17 bomber “Stage Door Canteen” in England in April 1944 with Mary Churchill Soames, General Frederick Anderson, and actors Vivien Leigh and Laurence Olivier present for the christening.
  - "Mr. Churchill's Cuba Trip" (color), 8 minutes, circa 1945 (Reel 25)
    Use copy reference number: 75054_f_0002069